# CV - Dario Ramon Landwehr

✓ dario.landwehr43@gmail.com

in Dario Landwehr

+45 53337518

★ Howitzvej 11, 5, 2000 Frederiksberg

# **Profile**

Junior Social Data Science scholar with degrees in Political- and Social Data Science. Interested in quantitatively tackling political and social puzzles using unstructured data sources and NLP. Additionally, my extracurricular involvement and experiences in different interdisciplinary research projects where I obtained many skills concerning project management and organization, are key strengths.

# **Employment History**

01/2024 – today

■ Pre-Doctoral Researcher. Department of International Economics, Government and Business, Copenhagen Business School. Denmark. Responsible for developing an interactive relational database, managing a team of student assistants, data [-analysis, -wrangling, -preprocessing] in Python. Project: "Who Became a Nazi? A structured Database of the Denazification Questionnaires".

02/2022 - 11/2023

■ Student Assistant. Department of Global Health, University of Copenhagen. Denmark. Writing of reports and deliverables, planning of stakeholder workshops, quantitative data analysis. Project: EU H-2020 "LINKS" on social media and crowd-sourcing in disaster management.

12/2022 - 06/2023

■ Social Data Science Studentship Copenhagen Center for Social Data Science, University of Copenhagen, Denmark. Data collection of a large parliamentary speech corpus through web scraping and APIs. Training of supervised machine learning models for classification. Multivariate data analysis (in Python). Project: "Mainstreaming of Populist Radical Right Language".

02/2021 - 03/2023

■ Intern. Institute for Parliamentary Research (IParl). Berlin, Germany. Data analysis (in R) and research concerning political candidate selection processes during the German federal election.

12/2022 - 06/2023

■ **Student Assistant.** German Center for Higher Education (DZHW). Hannover, Germany. Data analysis, literature research, survey and programming testing. Project: Nationa Educational Panel Study.

## **Education**

09/2021 - 01/2024

M.Sc. Social Data Science, University of Copenhagen.

Thesis title: Encoding Divides - Using Siamese Neural Networks for Measuring Partisan Differences from Political Speech.

GPA: 10.1 (on a scale of -3 to 12)

Focus: NLP, causal inference, machine learning for social sciences.

10/2018 - 07/2021

■ B.A. Political Science (with distinction), Leibniz University Hannover.

Thesis title: *Determinants of Incongruent Coalition Formation in the German Länder*. GPA: 1.3 (on a scale of 5.0 to 1.0)

Focus: Quantitative methods, comparative politics, political sociology.

# **Publications & Conferences**

### **Publications**

- B. Höhne, A. Bouju, and D. Landwehr, "Supporting diversity on party lists: Attitudes of german party gatekeepers towards enhancing immigrant representation," *Representation*, pp. 1–20, 2023, %.
- A. B. Nielsen, D. Landwehr, J. Nicolai, T. Patil, and E. Raju, "Social media and crowdsourcing in disaster risk management: Trends, gaps, and insights from the current state of research," Risk, Hazards & Crisis in Public Policy, pp. 1–24, 2024, .
- A. B. Nielsen, E. Raju, D. Landwehr, J. E. Nicolaï, T. Patil, and N. B. Andersen, "Leveraging social media and crowdsourcing in disaster risk management processes in europe," *Research Report*, 2023, %.

#### **Conferences**

- "Selling out? rhetorical mainstreaming of radical right parties," Accepted for presentation at EPSA's 14th annual conference, Cologne, 2024.
- "Supporting diversity on party lists. attitudes of party gatekeepers in (dis)-enhancing immigrants' representation," Annual Conference of the German Political Science Association's (DVPW) Section for Party Politics, Jena, 2021.

Populist Radical Right Language" (50.000 DKK).

# Other Experiences

## **Scholarships**

12/2022 ■ Social Data Science Studentship, Granted by the Center for Social Data Science (University of Copenhagen) for 6 months to work in the project "Mainstreaming of

o9/2022 ■ **DAAD Scholarship for Master Studies Abroad**, Granted by the German Academic Exchange Foundation (DAAD) for 12 months to pursue my M.Sc. degree at the Universy of Copenhagen (13.075 €).

#### **Extracurricular Work & Qualifications**

o4/2019 − o7/2021 Student Parliament "Fachrat Politik" Leibniz University Hannover. Advising the student body, in particular first-year students, representative in the examination committee.

o5/2019 − o4/2020 **Students for Future Hannover**. Organisation of events, especially the Public Climate School.

10/2019 - 03/2020 Mit Leibniz in den Beruf. Business administration and project management.

### **Skills**

Languages German (native), English (C1), Danish (A2).

Coding Python (Pandas, sklearn, numpy, selenium, matplot, NLTK) R (Data analysis, wrangling, plotting) 图EX

Office Word, Excel, PowerPoint